Ing. František Ferko

Summary

Web developer with experience backend and frontend development and development of reliable, scalable and secured applications in agile environment.

	Language	Duration	Year	Description
1	РНР	4 years	2013 - 2017	Development and maintenance of web backend technologies
2	JavaScript (ES5, ES6)	3+ years	2014 - 2017	AngularJS, jQuery, Ajax and pure JavaScript projects
3	TypeScript 2+	8 months	2017+	Angular 2+, SPA, RxJs
4	MySQL	4 years	2013 - 2017	Using MySQL databases together with PHP backend and Spring (Java) solutions
5	MongoDB	1+ year	2016	Using mongoDB as a database for symphony 2 based project
6	Symfony 2	2 years	2014 - 2016	Created custom CMS system, Form Builder project for non-profit ogranization
7	Zend 2	1 year	2014	Development of web application for e-commerce
8	Spring (Java)	< 1 year	2016 - 2017	Creating custom Rest API for social network (own project), JWT based authentification
9	HTML (responsive design)	4 years	2013 - 2017	Creating responsive web designs, Bootstrap, SemanticUI
10	CSS (sass, less)	4 years	2013 - 2017	Creating responsive web designs, Bootstrap, SemanticUI

11	Building Tools (Grunt, gulp, webpack)	3+ years	2014 - 2017	Using Grunt, Gulp and Webpack for compile assets
12	Agile Development	3+ years	2014 - 2017	Working in fully agile team, Rally, Jira, Redmine and other

Education

Technická univerzita v Košiciach

Bachelor's degree Informatization of proceses 2011 – 2014

Technická univerzita v Košiciach

Engineer degree Informatization of proceses 2014 – 2016

Work Experience

Date: 1.5.2017 - present
Employer: Wirecard GmbH (Košice)
Job position: Frontend developer

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, Angular 2+, SCSS, Highcharts, RxJs)

Working on single page web applications in finance

area

• Webpack, Git, Jenkins

Date: 14.2.2016 - 30.4.2017
Employer: Solar Turbines (NESS KE)
Job position: Full stack developer

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Angular.js, SCSS, Highcharts)

• Backend development (Spring, Hibernate, Oracle)

Single page web application for health management of turbines

• Grunt, Git, Jenkins

• Based in San Diego, California

Date: 1.6.2016 - present

Employer: -

Job position: Frontend developer

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SCSS, Bootstrap)

- Development of web projects for commercial clients (B2B web applications)
- Git
- Austrian client

Date: 10.10.2016 - 22.10.2016

Employer: Own project

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery, SASS)

Development of my presentation website http://www.ferkof.com

• Responsive web design (mobile first design)

Date: 1.2.2015 – 14.2.2016

Employer: Ness KE

Job position: Full stack developer

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SCSS, Bootstrap, jQuery)

 Backend development (PHP, Symfony 2, IonizeCMS, MySQL, Doctrine ORM)

 Development of websites projects for commercial clients (approx. 6 projects)

- Responsive web design (mobile first design)
- Communication with customers
- Git
- Based in Košice

Date: 1.7.2015 - 1.8.2015

Employer: Own project

Activities and responsibilities:

• Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, ¡Query)

- Backend development (IonizeCMS)
- Development of website for presentation purposes
- http://www.monikine-torty.sk
- Responsive web design (mobile first design)

Date: 1.10.2015 - 10.10.2015

Employer: Own project

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery)

- Backend development (IonizeCMS)
- Development of website for presentation purposes
- Responsive web design (mobile first design)

Date: 1.8.2015 - 1.2.2016

Employer: Own project (Diploma thesis)

Activities and responsibilities:

 Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Twig, Ajax, Javascript)

 Backend development (PHP, Symfony 2, MySQL, Doctrine ORM)

- Development of CMS system named FrostyCMS
- Database design and maintenance
- Responsive web design (mobile first design)

Date: 1.6.2014 – 31.12.2014 Employer: KeyUp Premium IT Services

Job position: Web Developer

Activities and responsibilities:

- Frontend development (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery)
- Backend development (Symfony 2, MySQL)
- Development of websites projects for commercial clients
- Responsive web design (mobile first design)
- Based in Košice

Language skills

English - B2

Slovak - native speaker

Czech - native speaker